In this video, lets delve deeper and get
even better intuition about what the cost
在这段视频中 让我们更深刻的研究更直觉的体会代价函数是来干什么的
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
function is doing. This video assumes that
you're familiar with contour plots. If you
此视频以你熟悉等高线图的绘制为前提
are not familiar with contour plots or
contour figures some of the illustrations
如果你不熟悉等高线图 这个视频中的某些描述
in this video may or may not make sense to
you but is okay and if you end up skipping
对你来说明确或者不明确都没关系 如果你因为以前没有见过等高线
this video or some of it does not quite
make sense because you haven't seen
而跳过这个视频或跳过一部分视频也不会有多大的影响
contour plots before. That's okay and you will
still understand the rest of this course
如果没有这部分知识 你仍然能理解这门课程的其他内容
without those parts of this. Here's our
problem formulation as usual, with the
下面是我们的问题 和往常一样
hypothesis parameters, cost function, and
our optimization objective. Unlike
有假设参数 代价函数 和我们的优化目标
before, unlike the last video, I'm
going to keep both of my parameters, theta
不像上次的视频那样 在对代价函数以可视化时 我要保留我所有的参数 θ0 和 θ1
zero, and theta one, as we generate our
visualizations for the cost function. So, same
所以像上次一样的
as last time, we want to understand the
hypothesis H and the cost function J. So,
我们想了解假设函数h和代价函数 J 因此
here's my training set of housing prices
and let's make some hypothesis. You know,
这里是我的训练集的住房价格 让我们做一些假设
like that one, this is not a particularly
good hypothesis. But, if I set theta
像这一个 这是不是一个特别好的假设 但是当我设置 θ0=50
zero=50 and theta one=0.06, then I end up
with this hypothesis down here and that
和 θ1= 0.06 那么我就得到了对应这条直线的以下一假设
corresponds to that straight line. Now given
these value of theta zero and theta one,
既然 θ0 和 θ1 被如此赋值
we want to plot the corresponding, you
know, cost function on the right. What we
我们要在右边绘制相应的 你知道 代价函数
did last time was, right, when we only had
theta one. In other words, drawing plots
像上次做的那样 当时 我们只有θ1
that look like this as a function of theta
one. But now we have two parameters, theta
因为函数只有一个参数 θ1 画出来的图像这样 但现在我们有两个参数
zero, and theta one, and so the plot gets
a little more complicated. It turns out
θ0 和 θ1 使图变得更复杂一点 事实证明
that when we have only one parameter, that
the parts we drew had this sort of bow
当我们只有一个参数 我们画的这部分想一个弓型的函数
shaped function. Now, when we have two
parameters, it turns out the cost function
现在 当我们有两个参数 代价函数有一个同样的弓型
also has a similar sort of bow shape. And,
in fact, depending on your training set,
而且事实上这取决于你的训练集
you might get a cost function that maybe
looks something like this. So, this is a
你可能会得到一个看起来像这样的代价函数
3-D surface plot, where the axes
are labeled theta zero and theta one. So
这是一个3D曲面图 轴标为 θ0 和 θ1
as you vary theta zero and theta one, the two
parameters, you get different values of the
所以 当你改变 θ0 θ1 这两个参数 你会得到不同的代价函数
cost function J (theta zero, theta one)
and the height of this surface above a
J(θ0,θ1) 的值 从表面到关于θ0 θ1 特殊点的高度
particular point of theta zero, theta one.
Right, that's, that's the vertical axis. The
对 这是 这是竖轴
height of the surface of the points
indicates the value of J of theta zero, J
从表面到关于 θ0 θ1 特殊点的高度 就是 J (θ0,θ1) 的值
of theta one. And you can see it sort of
has this bow like shape. Let me show you
你可以看到 它像是有这样的碗型形状
the same plot in 3D. So here's the same
figure in 3D, horizontal axis theta one and
让我们在 3D 中展示这个图形 这是 3D 中的同样的图形 横轴 θ1
vertical axis J(theta zero, theta one), and if I rotate
this plot around. You kinda of a
竖直轴 J (θ0,θ1) 如果我旋转这个图形 你会找到点感觉
get a sense, I hope, of this bowl
shaped surface as that's what the cost
这个碗状曲面 就是代价函数的样子
function J looks like. Now for the purpose
of illustration in the rest of this video
为了在以下的视频中进行分析
I'm not actually going to use these sort
of 3D surfaces to show you the cost
我实际上不会使用 3D 曲面来展示代价函数 J
function J, instead I'm going to use
contour plots. Or what I also call contour
我要使用等高线图 或者称为等高图像
figures. I guess they mean the same thing.
To show you these surfaces. So here's an
这两个词意义相同 为了向你展示这些曲面 因此这里是等高线图的例子
example of a contour figure, shown on the
right, where the axis are theta zero and
显示在右侧 其中的轴线为 θ0和θ1
theta one. And what each of these ovals,
what each of these ellipsis shows is a set
和这些椭圆形 省略的展现了一系列
of points that takes on the same value for
J(theta zero, theta one). So
J(θ0,θ1) 值相等的点 所以
concretely, for example this, you'll take
that point and that point and that point.
具体地说 例如这个 这一点 这一点 这一点
All three of these points that I just
drew in magenta, they have the same value
我用红色标注的这三个点 它们具有相同的 J(θ0,θ1) 值
for J (theta zero, theta one). Okay.
Where, right, these, this is the theta
好 这些 这是它的θ0 θ1轴
zero, theta one axis but those three have
the same Value for J (theta zero, theta one)
但上述三个点具有相同的 J(θ0,θ1) 值
and if you haven't seen contour
plots much before think of, imagine if you
如果你没有见过的等高线图 想象一下
will. A bow shaped function that's coming
out of my screen. So that the minimum, so
呈现在我屏幕上的碗型函数 使它的值最小的
the bottom of the bow is this point right
there, right? This middle, the middle of
碗底的底部就是的这一点 对不对?
these concentric ellipses. And imagine a
bow shape that sort of grows out of my
这些同心椭圆的中心 想象一个碗的形状渐渐变成我屏幕上的样子
screen like this, so that each of these
ellipses, you know, has the same height
所以在我屏幕上的每一个椭圆的 你知道 都有有相同的高度
above my screen. And the minimum with the
bow, right, is right down there. And so
碗型的最小值 恰好在这里
the contour figures is a, is way to,
is maybe a more convenient way to
所以等高线图 也许是一个更方便的方式来显示函数 J
visualize my function J. [sound] So, let's
look at some examples. Over here, I have a
所以让我们来看看一些例子 在这里 我有一个特殊点
particular point, right? And so this is,
with, you know, theta zero equals maybe
你知道 θ0可能等于800
about 800, and theta one equals maybe a
-0.15 . And so this point, right, this
θ1可能等于-0.15 所以这点 对 红色的这点
point in red corresponds to one
set of pair values of theta zero, theta one
对应了一对θ0 θ1的值
and the corresponding, in fact, to that
hypothesis, right, theta zero is
事实上对于该假设而言 θ0约等于800
about 800, that is, where it intersects
the vertical axis is around 800, and this is
也就是说 它与垂直轴相交于800左右
slope of about -0.15. Now this line is
really not such a good fit to the
斜率约-0.15 现在 这条线是真的并没对数据进行一个很好的拟合
data, right. This hypothesis, h(x), with these values of theta zero,
对不对? 假设函数 h(x) 和θ0 θ1的值
theta one, it's really not such a good fit
to the data. And so you find that, it's
并没对数据进行一个很好的拟合 所以你会发现
cost. Is a value that's out here that's
you know pretty far from the minimum right
存在成本 是一个和最小值相比相当远的值
it's pretty far this is a pretty high cost
because this is just not that good a fit
这是一个相当高的成本 因为这并没有那么好地拟合数据
to the data. Let's look at some more
examples. Now here's a different
让我们来看看一些例子 现在 这里是一个不同的假设
hypothesis that's you know still not a
great fit for the data but may be slightly
同样并没有那么好地拟合数据 但可能会略好一点
better so here right that's my point that
those are my parameters theta zero theta
所以这里是我的点 这些是我的参数θ0 θ1的值 对吗
one and so my theta zero value. Right?
That's bout 360 and my value for theta
θ0大概等于360 θ1=0
one. Is equal to zero. So, you know, let's
break it out. Let's take theta zero equals
所以 你知道 让我们找出它 让我们把θ0=360
360 theta one equals zero. And this pair
of parameters corresponds to that
θ1=0 这对参数对应于这条假设函数
hypothesis, corresponds to flat line, that is, h(x) equals 360 plus zero
对应这条平行线 也就是 h(x)=360+0*x
times x. So that's the hypothesis. And
this hypothesis again has some cost, and
所以这是假设函数 这个假设函数同样具有一定的成本
that cost is, you know, plotted as the
height of the J function at that point.
要知道 这个成本即绘制在 J 函数在该点的高度
Let's look at just a couple of examples.
Here's one more, you know, at this value
让我们来看几个例子 这里还有一个 你知道 当给θ0这个值
of theta zero, and at that value of theta
one, we end up with this hypothesis, h(x)
给θ1那个值 我们最后又一次得到了假设函数 h(x)
and again, not a great fit to the data,
and is actually further away from the minimum. Last example, this is
不能非常拟合的数据 甚至离最小值有点远 最后一个例子
actually not quite at the minimum, but
it's pretty close to the minimum. So this
其实并不是最小值 但它是相当接近最小值的 因此
is not such a bad fit to the, to the data,
where, for a particular value, of, theta
并不是太坏的拟合该数据 其中 θ0 为一个特定的值
zero. Which, one of them has value, as in
for a particular value for theta one. We
这里有一个特定的值给 θ1
get a particular h(x). And this is, this
is not quite at the minimum, but it's
于是我们得到了一个特殊的 h(x) 这并不是最小值
pretty close. And so the sum of squares
errors is sum of squares distances between
但是已经相当接近了 因此误差的平方的总和是训练样本与假设函数的距离的
my, training samples and my hypothesis.
Really, that's a sum of square distances,
的平方的和 这真的是一个距离的平方的总和 对不对?
right? Of all of these errors. This is
pretty close to the minimum even though
所有的这些误差 都相当接近最小值 虽然依旧不是最小值
it's not quite the minimum. So with these
figures I hope that gives you a better
因此通过这些图 我希望你更好地理解
understanding of what values of the cost
function J, how they are and how that
关于代价函数 J 他们是如何拟合不同的假设函数
corresponds to different hypothesis and so as
how better hypotheses may corresponds to points
和当数据非常接近函数 J 的最小值
that are closer to the minimum of this cost
function J. Now of course what we really
假设函数到底能多好地拟合数据
want is an efficient algorithm, right, a
efficient piece of software for
我们真正想要的是一个高效的算法 一个高效的软件
automatically finding The value of theta
zero and theta one, that minimizes the
能自动找寻使 J 最小θ0 θ1
cost function J, right? And what we, what
we don't wanna do is to, you know, how to
我们不想做的事情是 编写这样一个软件
write software, to plot out this point,
and then try to manually read off the
那就是绘制这个点 然后再尝试手动读取读数
numbers, that this is not a good way to do
it. And, in fact, we'll see it later, that
这并不容易做到 而且事实上 我们会在之后看到它
when we look at more complicated examples,
we'll have high dimensional figures with
当我们看更复杂的例子 我们涉及到更多的参数 用到高维的图形
more parameters, that, it turns out,
we'll see in a few, we'll see later in
我们会在以后的课程中看到一些
this course, examples where this figure,
you know, cannot really be plotted, and
不能被真正绘制的例子
this becomes much harder to visualize. And
so, what we want is to have software
视觉上更难表达 所以 我们需要有软件
to find the value of theta zero, theta one
that minimizes this function and
找到使函数最小的θ0 θ1的值
in the next video we start to talk about
an algorithm for automatically finding
在接下来的视频中 我们谈谈自动寻找使函数 J 最小的
that value of theta zero and theta one
that minimizes the cost function J.
θ0 θ1的值的算法
【果壳教育无边界字幕组】翻译：antis  校对：Jaminalia